Undergraduate Education, Office of the Vice Provost for; Records ua510
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education Records
2006 September 3 - 2017 May 17
1980-1995
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany. Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education
ua510
6.42 cubic ft. 94 captures
This collection contains inactive records from the Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education (previously called the Office of Undergraduate Studies).
Historical Note
The Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education is an administrative office that operates under the Office of the Provost (Vice President for Academic Affairs). It is responsible for the coordination of undergraduate academics at the University: including curriculum policy and development, academic counseling and advisement, transfer student support, independent study and internships oversight, and publication of the Undergraduate Bulletin.
Scope and Contents
Materials in this collection include: daily correspondence of Deans of Undergraduate Studies (organized alphabetically in series 2 and by subject in series 3 and 4), budget documentation, faculty policy documentation, committee reports and minutes, conference and retreat materials, department subject files, planning documentation for Project Renaissance (series 5), and other materials that relate to the administration of undergraduate studies at the University.
Arrangement of the Collection
Arrangement of this collection is based partly on type of materials and partly on original creator. Series 1 contains the web archives for the Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education. Series 2 contains Day Books for several individuals, and materials are presented in their original order. Series 3 and 4 contain materials created, broadly speaking, by different Deans. Series 3 contains the earlier materials, and has been arranged alphabetically in the absence of original order. Series 4 is primarily composed of materials created by Sung Bok Kim during his term as Dean of Undergraduate Studies, and is arranged alphabetically to reflect the order in which the materials were filed by their creator. Series 5: Project Renaissance, contains materials that were found together, but lacked any semblence of order.
Acquisition Information
All of the materials in this collection were transferred to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives from a records storage room overseen by the Office of the Provost. 2016
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Web Archives
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted with the exception of Series 2: Day Books. Please contact the University Archivist for additional information.
Universities and colleges--Accreditation.; Accreditation (Education); Education, Higher--Administration.; Web Archives; Administrative records; Letters (correspondence); Memorandums; UAlbany Academic Administration; Wages -- New York (State); State University of New York at Albany; State University of New York at Albany. Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education
- Website for the Office of Undergraduate Education, 2006 September 3 - 2017 May 17; 1; 94 captures
  URL
  http://www.albany.edu/undergraduateeducation/
  Access Requirements
  The item contains web archives preserved as WARC files. They must be access though web archival replay tools such as the "Wayback Machine." The links here direct you to files hosted by the Internet Archive, but you may also request WARC files.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Web crawling is managed through the Internet Archive's Archive-It service.
  This item is not a seed within an Archive-it collection, but capures of this page are found within:
  collection: University at Albany, SUNY Website
  created_date: 2012-09-17T13:15:00Z
  created_by: bkeough
  state: ACTIVE
  last_updated_date: 2016-09-26T23:38:05Z
  last_updated_by: system
  Web Collection
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2006 September 3
    This crawl was performed by the Internet Archive, not the UAlbany web archiving program, so the provenance is unknown.
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2007 February 19
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2007 October 27
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2008 June 8
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2008 October 16
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2009 January 22
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2009 January 22
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2009 March 25
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2009 August 15
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2009 October 15
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2010 April 21
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2010 May 27
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2010 June 23
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2011 January 7
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2011 June 23
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2011 July 6
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2011 September 26
  - Office of the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education, 2012 January 4
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2012 April 23
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2012 June 18
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2012 July 1
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2012 July 23
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2012 September 22
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2012 November 22
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2012 December 1
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 January 2
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 January 22
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 February 1
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 February 17
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 April 1
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 May 8
    This item had no crawl rules.
    The CDX index for this capture did not contain crawl information.
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 May 8
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Researchers interested in data analysis with web archives may request a WARC file. WARC files are very large and difficult to work with. Your request may take time to process, and we may be unable to deliver your request remotely. Please consult an archivist if you are interested in advanced research with web archives.
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 May 8
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 May 8
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 July 10
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 July 10
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 July 24
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 July 24
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 August 1
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 August 28
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 August 28
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2013 September 1
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 January 1
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 January 1
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 March 19
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 March 19
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 April 9
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 April 9
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 April 23
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 April 23
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 July 9
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 July 9
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 July 30
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 July 30
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 October 5
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 October 8
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 October 8
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 December 24
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2014 December 24
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 January 7
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 January 7
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 February 4
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 February 4
  - EOP Homepage - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 February 11
  - EOP Homepage - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 February 11
  - WARC file for EOP Homepage - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 February 11
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 February 18
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 February 18
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 June 3
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 June 3
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 June 17
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 June 17
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 July 11
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 July 17
    crawl: 165088
    Crawl Times
    start_date: 2015-07-17T16:55:07Z
    original_start_date: 2015-07-17T16:55:07Z
    last_resumption: None
    processing_end_date: 2015-07-22T22:02:18Z
    end_date: 2015-07-22T21:28:19Z
    elapsed_ms: 448383534
    Crawl Types
    type: MONTHLY
    recurrence_type: MONTHLY
    pdfs_only: False
    test: False
    Crawl Limits
    time_limit: 432000
    document_limit: None
    byte_limit: None
    crawl_stop_requested: None
    Crawl Results
    status: FINISHED_TIME_LIMIT
    discovered_count: 518483
    novel_count: 22064
    duplicate_count: 310947
    resumption_count: 0
    queued_count: 185472
    downloaded_count: 333011
    download_failures: 280
    warc_revisit_count: 310940
    warc_url_count: 332912
    total_data_in_kbs: 92321075
    duplicate_bytes: 89386949991
    warc_compressed_bytes: 975896456
    Crawl Technical Details
    doc_rate: 0.74
    kb_rate: 205.0
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2015 July 17
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 January 17
    crawl: 191947
    start_date: 2016-01-17T16:55:00Z
    original_start_date: 2016-01-17T16:55:00Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-01-22T17:27:17Z
    end_date: 2016-01-22T16:56:58Z
    elapsed_ms: 432114027
    discovered_count: 573952
    novel_count: 20681
    duplicate_count: 273347
    queued_count: 279924
    downloaded_count: 294028
    download_failures: 181
    warc_revisit_count: 273342
    warc_url_count: 293928
    total_data_in_kbs: 63947333
    duplicate_bytes: 64312716410
    warc_compressed_bytes: 176478309
    doc_rate: 0.68
    kb_rate: 147.0
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 January 17
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 February 17
    crawl: 196723
    Crawl Rules
    Ignore Robots.txt for www.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for www.alumni.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for www.ualbanysports.com (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for library.albany.edu (last updated 2017-05-19)
    Ignore Robots.txt for alumni.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for asrc.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for atmos.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for bioinformatics.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for cela.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for choose.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for cs.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for csda.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for imls.ctg.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for www.ctg.albany.edu (last updated 2017-05-19)
    Ignore Robots.txt for cwig.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for events.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for hr.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for ibl.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for illiad.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for liblogs.albany.edu (last updated 2017-05-19)
    Ignore Robots.txt for libguides.library.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for scholarsarchive.library.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for listserv.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for m.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for math.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for omega.math.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for mumford.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for nyjm.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for pdp.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for resnet.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for rit.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for cyberphysics.rit.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for rna.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for slsc.albany.edu (last updated 2017-05-19)
    Ignore Robots.txt for uaems.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for uapps.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    Ignore Robots.txt for wiki.albany.edu (last updated 2016-02-11)
    start_date: 2016-02-17T16:57:12Z
    original_start_date: 2016-02-17T16:57:12Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-02-23T04:10:10Z
    end_date: 2016-02-22T23:20:27Z
    elapsed_ms: 454987781
    discovered_count: 7638127
    novel_count: 795824
    duplicate_count: 806868
    queued_count: 6035435
    downloaded_count: 1602692
    download_failures: 248
    warc_revisit_count: 806856
    warc_url_count: 1602561
    total_data_in_kbs: 226292461
    duplicate_bytes: 193554304269
    warc_compressed_bytes: 633147239
    doc_rate: 3.52
    kb_rate: 497.0
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 February 17
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 March 13
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 March 17
    crawl: 201840
    start_date: 2016-03-17T16:54:59Z
    original_start_date: 2016-03-17T16:54:59Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-03-22T18:02:10Z
    end_date: 2016-03-22T16:56:57Z
    elapsed_ms: 432107388
    discovered_count: 639552
    novel_count: 138564
    duplicate_count: 332568
    queued_count: 168420
    downloaded_count: 471132
    download_failures: 1411433
    warc_revisit_count: 332563
    warc_url_count: 471037
    total_data_in_kbs: 116820623
    duplicate_bytes: 113225737713
    warc_compressed_bytes: 765920585
    doc_rate: 1.09
    kb_rate: 270.0
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 March 17
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 June 17
    crawl: 220038
    start_date: 2016-06-17T16:55:03Z
    original_start_date: 2016-06-17T16:55:03Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-06-23T01:46:32Z
    end_date: 2016-06-22T19:28:00Z
    elapsed_ms: 441165235
    discovered_count: 8887536
    novel_count: 557229
    duplicate_count: 1067492
    queued_count: 7262815
    downloaded_count: 1624721
    download_failures: 247
    warc_revisit_count: 1067450
    warc_url_count: 1624592
    total_data_in_kbs: 251943396
    duplicate_bytes: 239433481575
    warc_compressed_bytes: 1787914405
    doc_rate: 3.68
    kb_rate: 571.0
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 June 17
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 August 17
    crawl: 231044
    Block host dev.library.albany.edu
    start_date: 2016-08-17T16:58:06Z
    original_start_date: 2016-08-17T16:58:06Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-08-23T01:20:50Z
    end_date: 2016-08-22T23:33:45Z
    elapsed_ms: 455703830
    discovered_count: 1189467
    novel_count: 184079
    duplicate_count: 736427
    queued_count: 268961
    downloaded_count: 920506
    download_failures: 267
    warc_revisit_count: 736404
    warc_url_count: 920384
    total_data_in_kbs: 202254345
    duplicate_bytes: 198029314926
    warc_compressed_bytes: 397770039
    doc_rate: 2.02
    kb_rate: 443.0
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 August 17
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 November 17
    crawl: 249672
    start_date: 2016-11-17T16:57:23Z
    original_start_date: 2016-11-17T16:57:23Z
    processing_end_date: 2016-11-22T23:26:30Z
    end_date: 2016-11-22T18:15:59Z
    elapsed_ms: 436686458
    discovered_count: 6455397
    novel_count: 904107
    duplicate_count: 647491
    queued_count: 4903799
    downloaded_count: 1551598
    download_failures: 287
    warc_revisit_count: 647445
    warc_url_count: 1551482
    total_data_in_kbs: 234676600
    duplicate_bytes: 166348006398
    warc_compressed_bytes: 22645478722
    doc_rate: 3.55
    kb_rate: 537.0
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2016 November 17
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2017 January 17
    crawl: 261028
    start_date: 2017-01-17T17:03:42Z
    original_start_date: 2017-01-17T17:03:42Z
    processing_end_date: 2017-01-23T00:48:05Z
    end_date: 2017-01-22T19:31:33Z
    elapsed_ms: 440845477
    discovered_count: 6856243
    novel_count: 810250
    duplicate_count: 844972
    queued_count: 5201021
    downloaded_count: 1655222
    download_failures: 351
    warc_revisit_count: 844920
    warc_url_count: 1655090
    total_data_in_kbs: 260833049
    duplicate_bytes: 210669517964
    warc_compressed_bytes: 15598206209
    doc_rate: 3.75
    kb_rate: 591.0
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2017 January 17
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2017 March 17
    crawl: 273971
    start_date: 2017-03-17T16:55:07Z
    original_start_date: 2017-03-17T16:55:07Z
    processing_end_date: 2017-03-22T22:25:00Z
    end_date: 2017-03-22T18:08:47Z
    elapsed_ms: 436406787
    discovered_count: 7409222
    novel_count: 690900
    duplicate_count: 1257496
    queued_count: 5460826
    downloaded_count: 1948396
    download_failures: 359
    warc_revisit_count: 1257455
    warc_url_count: 1948270
    total_data_in_kbs: 266864045
    duplicate_bytes: 245675593330
    warc_compressed_bytes: 1581675727
    doc_rate: 4.46
    kb_rate: 611.0
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2017 March 17
  - Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2017 May 17
    crawl: 301465
    Host Rule Type C CONTAINS meg.library.albany.edu:8080/archive/search? (last updated 2017-05-11)
    start_date: 2017-05-17T16:55:17Z
    original_start_date: 2017-05-17T16:55:17Z
    processing_end_date: 2017-05-23T00:29:43Z
    end_date: 2017-05-22T21:46:25Z
    elapsed_ms: 449440076
    discovered_count: 2923335
    novel_count: 388249
    duplicate_count: 1238165
    queued_count: 1296921
    downloaded_count: 1626414
    download_failures: 336
    warc_revisit_count: 1238113
    warc_url_count: 1626286
    total_data_in_kbs: 265327774
    duplicate_bytes: 251274786133
    warc_compressed_bytes: 3306915146
    doc_rate: 3.62
    kb_rate: 590.0
  - WARC file for Undergraduate Education - University at Albany-SUNY, 2017 May 17
- Day Books, 1982-1993; 2; 0.66 cubic ft.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access to this series is restricted because it contains correspondence that references personally identifiable information. Access must be arranged through the University Archivist.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains an partial run of the daily correspondence for three Deans of Undergraduate Studies who served between 1982 and 1993: Leonard Lapinski, Harry Hamilton, and Sung Bok Kim. This correspondence was kept in binders organized by year, and this arrangement has been preserved. Topics addressed include grading policies and specific grading actions, registration policies, program and course revisions, personnel issues, budget decisions, and other policy issues that affect undergraduate education.
  - Leonard Lapinski(1 of 2), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Leonard Lapinski(2 of 2), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Leonard Lapinski (1 of 2), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Leonard Lapinski (2 of 2), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Harry Hamilton(1 of 2), 1983 September-1984 March (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Harry Hamilton(2 of 2), 1983 September-1984 March (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Harry Hamilton(1 of 2), 1984 April-1985 June (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Harry Hamilton (2 of 2), 1984 April-1985 June (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Sung Bok Kim, 1992 June-1993 June (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Dean of Undergraduate Studies (Desfosses, Hamilton), 1977-1987; 3; 0.5 cubic ft.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  This series consists of records created by the Office of the Dean of Undergraduate Studies between 1977 and 1987. The two Deans who served during this period were Helen Desfosses and Harry Hamilton. Materials include travel policy documentation, planning documents from the Medical Minority Recruitment Program Committee, and a run of The Forum for Liberal Education, published by the Association of American Colleges.
  - Albany Medical Recruitment Program, 1978-1981; 1983; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Institute of Higher Education, Salute to Faculty, 1985; 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Careers in Foreign Service, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1984; 1985; 1986; 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Forum, 1977; 1978; 1979; Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Forum, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Forum, 1980-1983; 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hudson-Mohawk Association of Colleges and Universities, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Mail Room Procedures, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - New York African American Institute, 1986; 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Personnel, 1981; 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - ROTC, 1980-1985; Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - SUNY Central- New Liberal Arts, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Travel, 1981; 1982; 1984; 1985; 1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Dean of Undergraduate Studies (Kim, Scatton, Pipkin), 1978-1997; 1985-1995; 4; 4.2 cubic ft.